<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Causal structure inference: IC algorithm and SEM model</title>
      <link>/2020/11/17/causal-structure-inference-ic-algorithm-and-sem-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/11/17/causal-structure-inference-ic-algorithm-and-sem-model/</guid>
      <description> Why we study causal structure of traits?  Reference  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLUE or BLUP: Which should be used for GWAS and GS?</title>
      <link>/2020/09/22/blue-or-blup-which-should-be-used-for-gwas-and-gs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/22/blue-or-blup-which-should-be-used-for-gwas-and-gs/</guid>
      <description>From the breeder&#39;s aspect, BLUP (best linear unbiased predictor) is commonly used for selection because it maximizes the probability of correct ranking (Searle and McCulloch 2001, chap. 9, p.254).
On the other hand, using BLUEs (best linear unbiased estimators) of genotypes as response variables for association mapping or genomic prediction has been a conventional approach, but the reason for using BLUEs instead of BLUPs is unclear to me and not explained in the most of papers I found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-stage analysis to compute BLUPs</title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/two-stage-analysis-to-compute-blups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/two-stage-analysis-to-compute-blups/</guid>
      <description>Why we use two-stage analysis? In plant breeding program, candidate genotypes may be tested in multiple environments, e.g. locations and years, to reliably evaluate quantitative traits. Data obtained from multi-environmental trials (MET) is typically analyzed by using mixed models that provide best linear unbiased estimators (BLUEs) and best linear unbiased predictors (BLUPs).
A standard approach to analyze MET data is by fitting all fixed and random effect with one stage, called single stage analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
