<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>test hugo</title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/test-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/test-hugo/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
When you click the Knit button a document will be generated that includes both content as well as the output of any embedded R code chunks within the document. You can embed an R code chunk like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-stage analysis to compute BLUEs and BLUPs</title>
      <link>/2020/09/18/two-stage-analysis-to-compute-blues-and-blups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/18/two-stage-analysis-to-compute-blues-and-blups/</guid>
      <description>Why we use two-stage analysis? In plant breeding program, candidate genotypes may be tested in multiple environments, e.g. locations and years, to reliably evaluate quantitative traits. Data obtained from multi-environmental trials (MET) is typically analyzed by using mixed models that provide best linear unbiased estimators (BLUEs) and best linear unbiased predictors (BLUPs).
A standard approach to analyze MET data is by fitting all fixed and random effect with one stage, called single stage analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Che-Wei Chang I am is currently a PhD student in the Group of Crop Biodiversity and Breeding Informatics (https://evoplant.uni-hohenheim.de/index.html) at the University of Hohenheim, Germany.
My research project focuses on the local adaptation of wild barley and the implementation of genomic prediction in barley breeding.
This personal web page is used to
Education  B.Sc. in Agronomy, National Taiwan University, Taiwan, 2015 M.Sc. in Crop Science, Group of Genetic Breeding, National Taiwan University, Taiwan, 2017  Publication  CW Chang, YH Wang, CW Tung.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
